# 瞧瞧 焦黄 脆脆的
Look! Golden and crispy
# 真好
So good
# 网友粉丝们 大家好
Hello friends and fans
# 因为YQ的发生
Because of the epidemic
# 好久没跟大家见面了
Haven’t seen you guys for a while
# 大爷想死你们了
I really miss you guys
# 今天给大家做一个家庭版的肉饼
Today I’m gonna show you how to make homemade meat pies
# 拍摄的人是我们老伴儿 成老师
My wife, Shifu Cheng, is shooting today’s video
# 也是你们大妈
You may refer to her as "Da Ma" as well
# 大家好
Hi everyone
# 现在就开始 先和面
Let’s get started with kneading the dough
# 和面很重要
kneading the dough is very important
# 我们常说叫
We often say
# 软面饺子硬面汤
Soft dough for dumplings, hard dough for noodles
# 烙饼的面 肉饼的面
When preparing flatbread or meat pie
# 面一定要软和
The dough has to be soft
# 我今天和这个大约有二斤面
I'm using about 1 kilogram of flour
# 大约一斤面 大约六两水左右
You need about 600ml water for a kilogram of flour
# 就用凉水和就行了 和的要软
Just mix with cold water. The dough must be soft
# 多软啊 有的说拿不起个儿来
How soft? Some said so soft that you can’t pick it up
# 其实不是 它还能拿起个儿来的
But no, you should be able to pick it up
# 就是越软和越好
Still the softer the better
# 你和面用的是什么面 标准粉
What flour do you use for the dough? All-purpose flour
# 一定要用标准粉
You have to use all-purpose flour
# 用高筋粉不行
High gluten flour won’t work
# 高筋粉烙出面有劲儿
High gluten flour would make the dough too tough
# 刚开始和 面可能不太滋润
We just started to knead the dough, it might not be very moist
# 疙疙瘩瘩的
Not quite smooth
# 等让它和好以后 让它饧一会
Let it rest for a bit after done kneading
# 待会儿我们有一个二次再进行揉
We are going to knead it again later
# 这样的面就滋润了
So the dough would be moist
# 这面就和好了
And the dough is ready
# 找块布给它盖上 饧着
Cover it with a piece of cloth and let it rest
# 饧面这个环节大约得二十来分钟
It's going to rest for about 20 minutes
# 下一步咱就开始打馅儿
Next we are going to start making the filling
# 搁点盐 这是猪肉
Put in some salt and here’s pork
# 大约在十二克 根据肉的多少
About twelve grams. It depends on the amount of meat
# 胡椒 还搁胡椒呢
Also put in some pepper as well
# 什么胡椒 白胡椒
What kind? White pepper
# 酱油有很多种
There are many kinds of soy sauce
# 你随便 你喜欢吃哪种酱油都可以
Put whatever kind of soy sauce that you like
# 放点老抽
Putting in some dark soy sauce
# 放点黄酒
Put in some yellow rice wine
# 黄酒有绍兴黄酒
Typically it's Shaoxing rice wine
# 我今天用的是福建黄酒
But what I’m using today is Fujian rice wine
# 一般打馅家里边
Usually when we make fillings at home
# 都习惯用筷子用尺板
We use chopsticks or stir sticks
# 为了让这肉更加滋润
In order to make the meat more moist
# 我就用手打馅
But I will just use my hand to mix the filling
# 这样打出来以后会更好
After I mix like this it will be better
# 这油得最后放
The oil should be put in at last
# 这颜色还不太行
The color is not there yet
# 北方吃馅 都要搁酱油
Northerners always put soy sauce in their fillings
# 颜色稍微重一点
The color would be a little darker
# 南方有的馅
Fillings from the south
# 你像包子馅 饺子馅
Like baozi filling and dumpling filling
# 他们很少搁酱油
They rarely put in soy sauce
# 所以北方和南方在做馅当中
So between northern and southern filling recipes
# 有它的区别
There are differences
# 朝着一个方向
Only in one direction
# 你看这馅越摔越紧实
See the filling is becoming tenser after throwing it
# 越摔越有劲
Throw it more to be tenser
# 这郑大爷真卖力气
Da Ye is working really hard
# 这就好啦
That’s done
# 有时候为了让这馅还嫩一点
Sometimes to make the filling more tender
# 还可以打一点水
You can also put in some water
# 打水可以打葱姜酒水
You can put in some ginger and green onion wine
# 也可以打咱们普通的白水
Or just use water
# 这个肉馅很重要
The meat filling is really important
# 肥瘦大约是三比七
The proportion of fat and lean meat is 3 to 7
# 有的可能喜欢再吃肥一点的
Some of you might like the fat
# 可以四比六
You can also do 4 to 6
# 太瘦了就不行了
But you can’t make it too lean
# 太瘦这个馅打出来又硬
If it's too lean, the filling will be too tough
# 干 不香
Dry and doesn't smell good
# 这馅打好了
Now the filling is ready
# 你看看这打好的馅
Check out the filling
# 这个大家可能见的少 这叫尺板
You probably haven’t seen this before. This is a "Chi Ban" ("ruler")
# 有的管它叫馅尺子
Some would call it a filling ruler
# 包饺子 包包子
While making dumpling or baozi
# 有这么一个小玩意儿好使
This is very helpful
# 使筷子不得劲
Chopsticks don't work very well
# 这时候里边要放点油
And now put in some oil
# 好一点的花生油 葱油都行
Good peanut oil or green onion oil will do
# 再放点香油
And some sesame oil
# 给它封上拌匀
Now mix it well
# 大爷不是做面食的
Da Ye doesn’t specialize in pastries
# 功夫跟专业的老师还不太一样
He doesn’t do it like the professionals
# 主要是家庭版的
Only homemade editions
# 这边放点姜 切好了 放在上面
Now put in some ginger. Cut it and put it on the top
# 下边切葱 按照我个人体会
And now cut the green onion. As in my personal experience
# 这葱在我们拌馅的时候
When we make the filling
# 什么时候开始烙饼
The moment you start cooking the pie
# 什么时候这葱拌到馅里头去
You mix in the green onion
# 不要过早的拌 过早的拌
Don’t do it too early. If you do it too early
# 这葱经过和肉馅的接触
The green onion is in contact with the filling
# 因为肉馅里边有盐
Because there’s salt in the filling
# 一接触把这葱的味道就给泡出来了
It would make the smell of green onion very obvious
# 一泡出来以后有点臭葱味
Once that happen, the smell will be all over
# 这葱最有味的是哪儿啊
What's the part of a green onion with the strongest smell?
# 是葱尾巴和葱芯儿
The bottom and the inside
# 因为它里边含的水分大 葱味浓
Because it has more juice so the smell is stronger
# 甭管是吃包子 吃饺子
Regardless of baozi or dumpling
# 我们用点葱芯儿
We will use some green onion’s insides
# 大爷在家猫了有四十天了
Da Ye has been staying at home for about forty days
# 四十天干什么呢
What did I in the forty days
# 净做饭了 变着样儿的做
Just cooking. Making all the different dishes
# 这一变着样儿的做
Making all the variations
# 我们可感动了可感动了
We are really touched
# 感动吧 好吃
- Really touched?
- So tasty
# 看大妈都感动了
See Da Ma is touched
# 不光我一人感动 全家人都感动
Not just I’m touched, our whole family is touched
# 葱啊别剁得太碎 太碎了
Don’t chop the green onion too fine. If it's too fine
# 这个葱盐一出来水分就跑掉了
Once the green onion touches the salt it will lose all the juice
# 你看这葱不少吧
See we have quite some green onion
# 这馅呢 我们一会做的时候再和它
Let’s mix the filling again later while cooking
# 现在都弄好了 咱们休息一会儿
Now everything’s ready. Let’s rest a little
# 等会儿那个面饧好了 就开始烙
When the dough is ready, we will get started
# 行了 关机
Alright, turn the camera off
# 按这个 按这红的
Press that, press the red one
# 大爷开始烙饼了
Da Ye is making the meat pies now
# 大家看这面啊 很软
Check out the dough, it’s really soft
# 面一定要到这种程度
The dough has to be like this
# 因为它饧到家了
Because it has rested really well
# 饧到家以后 一揉 它就润了
Once it has rested well, we only need to knead a little
# 切成三个剂儿
Cut it into three
# 把这剂儿再分别揉一揉
And knead them separately
# 好了 我们把铛烧上
Alright Let’s heat up the pan
# 刚才说的啊 现拌
What we just mentioned, mix it now
# 这回把它和好了
Now it’s ready
# 有时候我们网友说
Sometimes ours fans ask
# 你怎么能看出来咸淡来啊
How can you tell if it’s salty enough
# 这些素的东西一放进去
When you put in the greens
# 它马上就会软 就塌下去了
It softens, and collapses immediately
# 就说明什么啊 盐够了
And that means it's salty enough
# 有的时候韭菜搁半天也不塌
Sometimes the Chinese chives don't collapse even after a long time
# 说明这盐不够 再补点盐
That means it's not salty enough and you need to add some more
# 闻着香吧 有香味了
Smells good right? The smell has come out
# 馅和好了啊 开始出剂儿
Filling is ready, let’s roll it
# 很多网友可能看见的都是擀的圆饼
Many of you guys might have seen round ones
# 今儿大爷家庭版擀长饼
Today Da Ye is going to make long ones
# 擀出这个剂儿是长条的
Rolling out long ones
# 这面活得好三下两下的 就推开了
If you did a good job kneading the dough, it’s easy to roll it
# 咱家自己吃就舍得搁肉
Let’s put in a lot of filling since it’s for our own family
# 好像别的时候不舍得似的
Sound like you are not willing to put in a lot other times
# 别太多了 不多
- Don’t put in too much
- It is not
# 把它抹匀了
Make it even
# 看着啊 折
Check it out! Fold
# 这边没有 往上折
- No filling at this part?
- Fold upwards
# 不抹那个肉
Don’t put filling here
# 为了折
For folding
# 一边折着把两边尽量封上
While folding, try to seal both sides
# 一边折一边封着
Fold while sealing
# 再折 四折了啊
Fold again, this is the fourth time now
# 最后这点很重要 五折
The last point is important, fifth fold
# 大爷这肉饼啊 不擀
Da Ye doesn't roll his meat pies
# 就拿手按 为什么不擀
- Only pressing with the hands
- Why not rolling it?
# 一擀啊 这馅跑了
Once you roll it, the filling would come out
# 有的我们在外边吃肉饼啊
Sometimes when we eat meat pies in restaurants
# 中间有时候没肉 肉跑哪去
There’s no meat in the middle. Where did all the meat go?
# 全跑边上去了
All on the edges
# 饼铛 搁点底油
Put in some base oil in the pan
# 在这里边呢 还要按一按
And press a little again here
# 让它再薄点
To make it a little thinner
# 你看 没有漏的吧 盖盖儿
See no filling has leaked out. Put on the lid now
# 第一张开始
Lets start with the first one
# 比平时烙饼的时间要长一些
It takes a little longer than usual
# 大约六分钟吧
about six minutes
# 闻着香味了吧 真好
You smell it? so good
# 这边再熥一下 那边再熥一下
Bake here a little and there as well
# 这个饼就齐了 焦黄焦黄的
Then the meat pie is ready. Golden and crispy
# 一看肉就多
So much filling
# 而且这面你看多滋润呀
Also check out the dough it’s so moist
# 大爷真行 不光会红案白案也行
Da Ye is so good, not just good at meat dishes but pastries as well
# 白案也凑合 真是大显身手啊
- Not too bad at pastries
- What a marvelous job!
# 按照大妈的需求
According to Da Ma’s request
# 咱们想办法做点好吃的
We are gonna try to make some good stuff to eat
# 真是 好了 熟啦
Ok it’s ready
# 大妈照一下 真棒
Da Ma take a picture, so good
# 漂亮吧 嘿 真棒
Isn’t it prefect? So good
# 改下刀 切成块
- Chop it up
- Cut it into pieces
# 看看层啊 都切完了
Check the layers. Done
# 焦黄焦黄的 哎呀太棒了
Golden and crispy. Wow it's so good
# 大妈给照一个
Da Ma take a picture
# 照一个照一个 必须照一个
Take a picture. Have to take one
# 怎样 大家看一下
How is it, let’s have a look
# 不同角度 多棒啊 太棒了
Different angles. How good! So great!
# 瞧瞧 焦黄
See? Golden brown
# 脆脆的 真好
Crispy. So good
# 我先尝尝 大爷先尝一口
- Let me try it
- Da Ye get a bite first
# 怎么样 没问题 香
How is it? No problem, smells so good
# 走喽
Let’s go
# 上菜
Serve it up
# 开吃
Let’s get started
# 家有大厨 就是幸福
Having a chef at home is awesome
# 走你
Let's go!
import ending.srt 00:09:22,000 (请原样保留此行)